Fushi lives alongside Gugu and the others.
（観察者）
グーグーたちとの共同生活
Through his daily routines,
he slowly gains more stimulation.
日常の営みにおける細かな刺激が
フシに蓄積されていく
Following a falling-out with Gugu,
グーグーと仲たがいしたフシは
Fushi takes Pioran's advice to go and find him...
ピオランの助言を受け
家出したグーグーを捜しに向かう
And they reunite.
そして再会した
♪～
～♪
Look. I heard this is it.
（男）おい ここだってよ
This is where the monster lives?
ここが怪物の住みかか
I don't see anyone here.
（男）誰もいないじゃんか
I'm scared.
（女）なんか怖い
（地響き）
（３人）え？
（咆哮(ほうこう)）
There it is!
（３人の悲鳴）
It's the monster!
（女）わあ 出た！
（男）助けて
Nice, Fushi!
（グーグー）やったな フシ
（フシ）ヒヒッ
The stronger the stimulation,
the deeper it's engraved in memory.
（観察者）強い刺激ほど
より深く記憶に刻まれる
For example, encountering a monster.
たとえば怪物に出会うこと
（フシの咆哮と人々の悲鳴）
（男子たち）うわあ
（女性）ああ…
（女性の悲鳴）
（赤ちゃんの泣き声）
One boy became brothers with a monster.
（観察者）
ある少年は怪物と兄弟になった
（グーグー）ハッハッハッ…
見た あの顔？　ウケるよな
Did you see that face?
That was hilarious.
Gugu.
（フシ）グーグー
（グーグー）ん？
Aren't you going back to Booze Man's place?
（フシ）
帰らないの？　さけじいの所…
No way.
（グーグー）ヤダよ
Haven't you heard?
Beer Gramps put booze in me.
聞いてないのか？
俺は酒爺(さけじい)に酒を仕込まれたんだぞ
あ…
Gugu!
グーグー！
Weird...
（グーグー）な… んだ
I can't move my body.
体に力が… 入らない…
Deep Memories
（グーグー）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
I haven't had anything
to eat in a long time.
ずっと何も食べてないんだ
Fushi, do you have anything?
フシ 何か持ってる？
I don't.
もってない
Okay.
（グーグー）そっか…
（荒い息）
フゥ フゥ フゥ…
I got some!
I got some, Gugu!
出た！　出たよ グーグー
Wait, I'll make more.
待ってて また つくる
（フシ）あっ
（グーグー）ん？
I did it! Eat!
（フシ）できた！　食え
（グーグー）むぐ…
Yum!
うまい！
I never knew you could make food, too.
食い物も作れるのか お前？
The more something stimulated him,
the easier it was for him to create it.
（観察者）
フシは強く刺激を受けたものほど
たやすく作ることができた
Wow, this is amazing. What else can you make?
The stronger the stimulation,
the deeper it's engraved in memory.
強い刺激ほど 深く記憶に刻まれる
Only this.
Oh, okay...
But depending on how he grows going forward,
だが 今後の成長しだいでは
he may become able to recall
well and recreate things
少量の刺激で獲得できたものでも
よく思い出し
that he'd gained through
even slight stimulation.
呼び起こすことができるように
なるだろう
（グーグー）は～
もう 食べられないや
I'm so full.
（グーグー）ふっ
（犬の鳴き声）
（ミール）キュー
Joaan.
ジョアン…
Meer!
（グーグー）ミール！
また家から抜け出してきたのか？
Did you run away from home again?
Joaan.
That's not right.
ジョアン
（グーグー）違うよ
これはミール リーンの犬だ
This is Meer, Rean's dog.
What's that "Joaan" you mentioned?
てか ジョアンて何だ？
（フシ）ん… ジョアン…
Joaan...
Someone said that when he saw my face.
そう呼ぶ人いた
オレの顔 見たとき
Then that must be your name.
（グーグー）
じゃあ きっと お前の名前だな
Was it your parents who called you that?
呼んでたのは お前の親か？
I don't know.
わからない
But that person was my first person.
でも あの人
オレの はじめの人
He stopped moving and became
empty, so I became him.
動かなくなって
中身なくなったから
オレ その人になった
I see.
（グーグー）そういうことか
So the appearance you have now is someone
else's, and that person is dead now.
今の お前の外見は
元になってる人がいて
そいつは死んだってことか
Dead?
しんだ？
Yeah.
Their time came.
（グーグー）ああ 死を迎えたんだ
You could become a girl, too, right?
お前 女の子にもなれたろ
Did that girl die, too?
その女の子も死んだのか？
And that big bear and the wolf?
あの大きなクマやオオカミも？
What's "die"?
“し”ってナニ？
It's what you call becoming empty.
（グーグー）お前の言う
からっぽになるってやつさ
Once that happens, you can't
go back to how you were.
一度そうなったら
二度と元に戻れない
That's what death is.
それが死なのさ
You make new things in
reaction to pain, right?
お前は痛みに反応して
新しいものを作るんだよな
I wonder if that means you
react to emotional pain, too.
心の痛みにも
反応するってことなのかな
For example, if I die and you become
upset, you could become me.
たとえば俺が死んだことで
お前がショックを受けたら
俺にもなれる
That's how it works, right?
そういうことだろ？
I think so.
たぶん
Wow, that's cool. I really like that.
（グーグー）
いいな それ すごくいい
Why?
（フシ）なんで？
Even if I die, you'd still think of me.
（グーグー）俺が死んでも
俺は お前だけには
思ってもらえるってことじゃないか
Yeah.
I'm a loner, you know.
うん
（グーグー）
俺 独りぼっちだからさ
If I'd been born to a normal family,
I'd never miss a meal.
これが普通の家庭で育った子供なら
毎日欠かさずゴハンを食べてさ
I'd have a soft place to sleep.
ふかふかの寝床を用意してもらって
If I had a fever, I'd have a
mother to take care of me,
熱が出たら看病してくれる
お母さんがいて
and a father to ask, "How're you feeling?"
“調子はどうだ？”って
聞いてくれる お父さんがいて
And twin older siblings who can be mean,
but still make time to play with me.
意地悪だけど一緒に遊んでくれる
双子の姉ちゃんがいて
And an older brother who teaches me things.
俺に いろいろ教えてくれる
兄ちゃんがいてさ…
A normal life is one where a lot
of people think of you, right?
たくさんの人に思ってもらえる人生
それが“当たり前”ってやつだろ？
And... And then, one day,
I noticed something was wrong.
それで… それでさ
でも ある日 気づくんだ 違和感に
Come, children.
（母親）おいで 子供たち
We have cake.
ケーキを頂いたわ
一緒に食べましょう
Let's eat together.
Yay!
（姉）やったわ！
約束 覚えていてくれたのね
You remembered our promise!
Cherry cake, right?
（妹）チェリーのケーキでしょ
大好きなの！
I love cherry cake!
Wait, Gugu.
（グーグー）アハッ
（シン）待て グーグー
（グーグー）え？
Wait.
（グーグー）ん？
（シン）待て
That's the rule.
それがルールだ
What are you waiting for, you two?
あら なに遠慮してるのよ
あなたたち
Yeah.
（祖母）そうよ
こっちへ来て お食べなさい
Come over here and eat.
Okay. Thank you.
はい ありがとうございます
After a while, our family moved
because of my father's work.
（グーグー）しばらくすると
お父さんの仕事の関係で
家族は引っ越すことになった
But they didn't take us with them.
でも俺たちは
連れていってもらえなかった
It's just the two of us left.
２人きりに なっちまったな…
Well, where should we work next?
さあ これから どこで働くか？
The people I thought were family
were just our employers.
（グーグー）
俺が家族だと思っていた人たちは
ただの雇い主だった
The only one who thought
of me was my brother.
俺を思ってくれる人は ただ１人
兄ちゃんだけ
My brother was nice to me,
even when it was just the two of us.
兄ちゃんは２人になってからも
ずっと優しかった
But that's over now, too.
でも もう それも終わった
Things happened, and now I'm all alone.
何だかんだあって結局１人
But you're here now.
でも今は お前がここにいる
Sorry about the other day, Fushi.
こないだは ごめんな フシ
For hurting you.
お前を傷つけるようなことして…
If I die, become me, Fushi.
俺が死んだら 俺になってな フシ
Okay.
うん
ハハハ…
I'm kind of sleepy.
俺 なんだか ちょっと眠いや
Did you eat too much?
たべすぎ？
I'm really happy right now.
（グーグー）俺はさ…
今すごく うれしいんだ
Only you came here worried for me.
だって お前…
お前だけが俺を心配して
俺を思って ここに来てくれて…
It's almost like we're a real family.
それって何だか
本当の家族みたいだ
（グーグーの寝息）
Gugu?
（フシ）グーグー？
There you are! Way out here!
（リーン）いた！　こんな所に
Rean!
（グーグー）えっ リーン？
Sheesh. I looked everywhere for you, you know.
もう！　ずいぶん捜したのよ
How did you know I was here?
（グーグー）
なんで ここが分かったの？
I heard Meer barking.
ミールの声がしたのよ
He has a habit of running away from home.
この子 脱走グセがあるのよね
キュウ…
（リーン）んん…
はあ…
ぬう…
Why won't you come back?!
どうして帰らないの！
Why would you tell me to go back?!
（グーグー）どうして帰れなんて
言うんですか？
I'm a victim!
俺は被害者ですよ
The old man says he's sorry.
おじいさんね 反省してるって
He says he'll take the
thing out of your stomach.
おなかのものを
取ってあげるってさ 無料で
For free!
For free?!
（グーグー）
無料で？　当たり前ですよ！
Of course it'll be free!
So you're coming back, right?
で帰るでしょ？　さっさと行こう
Let's go.
Wait.
（グーグー）待って！
Does that mean everyone wants me back?
みんな 俺に戻ってほしいってこと？
どうして？
Why?
Everyone needs you.
みんな あなたが必要なのよ
大好きだから
We love you.
R-Really?
（グーグー）ほ… 本当？
Even you?
リーンさんも？
Yes.
ええ
Grandfather, Grandmother, I've made lunch.
おじいさん おばあさん
ゴハンを作ったわよ
（酒爺）あーん…
（酒爺）マズッ
（ピオラン）プヘッ
Why don't you cook for yourselves
if you have complaints?
文句言うなら
自分たちで作ったら？
Don't wanna.
（酒爺）イヤじゃ
Too much work.
（ピオラン）ダルい…
I'm not babysitting those two!
（リーン）あんな２人の
おもりなんて ごめんだわ
I'm not going back, though.
（グーグー）でも帰らない
ええ！
I threw away my mask.
（グーグー）俺は仮面を捨てました
That means I threw away
my life as a human being.
それは人間としての暮らしを
捨てたってことです
I thought that mask was
for attracting customers.
ん？　あの仮面は
客引きのためだったんじゃ？
I'm sorry. I lied.
（グーグー）
ごめんなさい ウソをつきました
That mask was for hiding my face injuries.
あれは顔のケガを隠すためなんです
You poor thing.
気の毒に… それで隠れてるのね
So that's why you're hiding.
（リーン）はっ！
（グーグー）えっ
Wh-What are you doing?!
な… 何をするんですか！
（リーン）はっ！
（グーグー）ひっ！
You're awful! Pervert! Lowlife!
ひどい 変態 サイテー！
What are you doing,
clinging to that tree like a bug?
何よ 虫みたいに
木に くっついちゃって
I don't care about your face.
あなたの顔なんて どうでもいいわ
Well, I care!
（グーグー）
俺には どうでもよくない！
I don't want people to see it!
見られたくないんです！　君に
Particularly you.
You were showing your face all this time.
顔 今まで ずっと
出してたのに なんで？
Why?
Just be quiet for a second.
（グーグー）
いや ちょっと黙ってて
What?
（リーン）何？　私の前では
顔を見せてはくれないってこと？
Are you saying you aren't
going to show me your face?
No, that's not really...
（グーグー）
いや そういうわけでは…
Fine.
分かったわ 仮面があれば
その虫ごっこをやめてくれるわね？
You'll stop pretending you're like
a bug if you have your mask, right?
I'll go get it.
取ってくるから
どこに捨てたか教えて
Tell me where you threw it out.
Gee, I don't remember.
（グーグー）
さあ… どこだったかな
Gugu.
Wh-What?
（フシ）グーグー
（グーグー）な… 何だよ？
ん？　おっ
Gugu, your chest hurts every
time you talk to Rean.
グーグー リーンと話すと
いつも胸いたい
（グーグー）えっ
Will it stop if you have your mask?
仮面 あれば なおる？
Wh-Wh-What is your problem?!
（グーグー）
ななな… 何なんだよ！
What are you talking about?!
お前 何言ってんだよ！
I'll go find it!
（フシ）さがしてくる！
H-Hey! Don't leave me here!
（グーグー）お… おい！
俺を置いていくな！
What a strange man.
ヘンな人ね フフッ
でも優しい
But he's kind.
Hey, want to see my wound?
ねえ 私の傷 見せてあげようか？
Huh?
（グーグー）ハッ えっ？
It's a really bad wound.
ひどいのよ 私の傷
It might make you realize
yours isn't that bad.
ひょっとしたら あなたの傷は
隠すほど ひどくないって⸺
思えるかもしれないでしょ
W-Wait!
（グーグー）ちょ… ちょっと！
See?
ねっ ひどいでしょ？
Isn't it bad?
That's nothing!
（グーグー）全然じゃないか！
Nothing?!
ぜん…
Th-That's awful!
ひ… ひどい！
すごく悩んでたのに
It's been weighing on me a lot!
It's a ball of snot compared to mine!
（グーグー）俺のケガに比べたら
鼻くそみたいですよ
Oh, really? Let's see yours, then!
（リーン）何よ！
じゃあ あんたのも見せなさいよ
（グーグー）ヤダ…
ヤダ ヤダ！
Listen, your wound's almost
completely healed!
（グーグー）あのですね
その傷は ほとんど
治ってるじゃないですか
You're an idiot for worrying about that!
そんなので悩むなんてバカ
An idiot!
バカですよ バカ！
大げさにも程がある
You can't seriously be so dramatic!
How could you...
何よ…
You say the same things Mom and Dad do.
（グーグー）ええっ
（リーン）あんたって
パパやママと同じこと言うのね
（グーグー）ああ…
ごめん ええと…
Sorry... Um...
Wait, things aren't going well with your parents?
え？　両親と
うまくいってないんだ？
Don't worry about me.
（リーン）
いいのよ 私のことなんて
I'm just being dramatic.
どうせ大げさですから
But... I mean...
（グーグー）いやあ でも…
ハハハ 泣かないで
Don't cry.
Come back, Fushi.
フシ 早く帰ってきて
Those people think I'm a pet or something.
（リーン）あの人たちは私を
ペットか何かだと思ってるんだわ
They want me to do everything as they say.
何でも思いどおりにしたがるの
They're horrible.
だって ひどいのよ
私は本当は紫が好きなのに
I like purple, but they keep buying me green
things because that's the family color.
家の色だからって
緑のものばかり買ってくるのよ
Huh? I like green.
（グーグー）
へ？　いいじゃない 緑
That's not all.
（リーン）それだけじゃないわ
I was drawing when Mom hired a teacher.
私が絵を描いていたら
ママは先生を雇ったの
I didn't like that, so I started knitting,
and then Mom hired a knitting teacher.
それがイヤで縫い物を始めたら
今度は縫い物の先生を雇ったの
I just want to be free.
私は自由にやりたいのに…
But I was always surrounded by grown-ups.
そう 私の周りには
常に大人たちがいたわ
Any time I'd sneeze,
someone would come to me.
私が くしゃみをしたら
必ず誰かが寄ってくる
They'd make me eat,
even when I said I wasn't hungry.
いらないって言っても
ゴハンを毎回 食べさせられる
They combed my hair four times a day.
髪を１日４回も とかされる
And even when I got sick of it and went
outside, a servant would come with me.
そんな家がイヤで 外へ出かけても
必ず侍女が ついてきた
I never had time to myself in my life.
私の人生に
１人の時間というものはないのよ
It's like they haven't accepted
me as an individual.
まるで１人の人間として
認められていないみたい
As long as I'm at that home...
あの家にいるかぎりね
That's so stupid.
（グーグー）バカバカしい
いい両親じゃないか
They sound like good parents.
You're the awful one.
ひどいのは君のほうだ
You count people's kindness as misfortune
and brag as though you're complaining.
人の思いやりを
わざわざ不幸の１つに数えて
自慢じみた愚痴を披露している
That's how it looks to me.
俺には そう見えるね
You've got the wrong idea!
勘違いしないで！
I never expected to be able
to share your values, either.
私だって あなたと価値観を
共有できるとは思ってないわ
I would have never had this wound
if I hadn't been born to that family.
この傷だって あの家に
生まれてなければ つかなかった
What?
（グーグー）はい？
Someone pushed me from behind.
誰かに後ろから押されたの
People say it must be
someone who hates my dad.
周りが言うには パパに恨みのある
人の仕業じゃないかって
Yet no one worries about me.
それなのに私のこと
全然 心配してくれないの
That's wrong.
（グーグー）違うよ
え？
Did you say I'm wrong?
今“違う”って言った？
No.
I said you're an idiot.
（グーグー）いや…
君はバカだって言ったんだ
Hey!
ちょっと！　今日だけで
何回バカって言ったのよ！
How many times can you call
me an idiot in one day?
ハッ
（グーグーの泣き声）
（ミール）キュウ
Hey, Meer...
（リーン）ねえ ミール
私 そんな ひどいこと言った？
Was what I said really that awful?
It woofsn't!
“言ってないワン”
Hey, how did you hurt your face?
（リーン）
ねえ なんで顔にケガしたの？
I'm not saying.
（グーグー）
言わない 言ったら嫌われるから
You'll hate me if I do.
What do you mean by that?
どういうことよ？
Do you like me?
私のこと好きなの？
I'm not saying.
（グーグー）
言わない 言ったら嫌われるから
You'll hate me if I do.
You're not telling me anything, huh?
何にも教えてくれないのね
I'm a freak.
（グーグー）俺は怪物だ
That's all you need to know.
それだけで十分だ
（リーン）ふーん…
ハッ えーと…
Um...
Oh, right!
あっ これ！　この仮面
The mask!
I brought this as a gift for you.
あなたにプレゼントするために
持ってきたやつなんだった
The old man says it's from
a traditional tribe.
おじいさんが言うには
伝説の民族のものなんですって
Isn't that amazing?
すごいわね よかったら使って
You can use it if you'd like.
I-I don't need this!
（グーグー）
い… いらないよ こんなもの
You're so silly.
（リーン）あなたってバカみたい
エヘッ
I don't care if you're a monster or a human.
あなたが怪物でも人間でも
私には どっちでもいいけどさ
You're still you either way, aren't you?
でも それって
どっちも あなたでしょ？
I like how weird you are either way,
全部さらけ出す あなたも
隠さずにはいられない あなたも
whether you're spilling your guts out
or you can't help but hide everything.
どっちもヘンで好きだけどな
That's you.
それが あなた
あなたは あなたよ
You're you.
Come out already.
ねえ 出てきなよ
You aren't going to avoid looking at
me for the rest of your life, are you?
まさか一生
目を合わせてくれないつもり？
I want to get to know you better.
私は あなたのことを
もっとよく知りたいわ
Even if you have to hide your face.
たとえ仮面をかぶってなきゃ
いけないとしてもね
Hey, the wind's nice.
ねえ 風が気持ちいいよ
フフッ
Fushi-san's taking his time, huh?
フシさん 遅いわね
待つ？　捜す？
Should we wait? Or should we look for him?
Let's go.
（グーグー）行こう
Sorry for the awful things I said earlier.
さっきは ごめん ひどいこと言って
What was it again?
（リーン）何だっけ？
（ニオイを嗅ぐ音）
Found it!
（フシ）あっタ！
Are you enjoying playing human?
（観察者）人間ごっこは楽しいか？
ふんっ
The enemy is always looking
for an opportunity.
（観察者）敵は いつでも
機会をうかがっている
（フシ）あ…
Be cautious.
（観察者）気をつけなさい
I threw my mask out over this way.
（グーグー）
この先で仮面を捨てたんだ
So Fushi should be around here, too.
だからフシも その辺にいるはず
Aren't we going to miss each other?
行き違いにならない？
Don't worry.
（グーグー）大丈夫だよ
あいつから俺らを見つけてくれる
He'll find us.
How do you know?
なんで分かるの？
Well, because he's him, of course.
（グーグー）そりゃあ
あいつが あいつだからさ
Say what? That makes no sense.
何それ？　意味分かんない…
キャッ
Rean-sama.
（グーグー）ん？
（男）リーン様 さあ帰りましょう
Let's go home now.
No! Let me go!
イヤよ 放して！
Wh-Who is he?
（グーグー）な… 何 その人？
He's a hired thug!
カネで雇われたゴロツキよ
I wonder how much money
he's making for catching me!
私を捕まえて
いくら もらえるのかしらね！
She's the Cropps' daughter.
（女性）クロップ家の娘さんよ
What, she ran away from home again?
（店主）何だ また家出したんか
Let me go!
（リーン）放せ 放せ！
（グーグー）ハッ
No!
イヤ！
（男）おわっ
Run!
（グーグー）走って！
（グーグーとリーンの荒い息）
Hey, you were running away from home?
（グーグー）ねえ 家出してたの？
Yeah, that's right.
ええ そうよ
I bet Dad's hired at least twenty people.
パパのことだから
20人は雇ってそうね
They're wandering around town to find me.
ヤツらは私を見つけるために
街を捜し回ってるんだわ
Why did you leave home?
（グーグー）どうして家出を？
全部 話してよ
Tell me everything.
What? I already told you.
（リーン）
あら さっき話したじゃない
What you told me earlier?
（グーグー）
さっきの話？　あれが？
That's it?
What? Is that weird?
何よ あれだとヘン？
I mean...
（グーグー）いや…
Was this mask so that
they wouldn't find you?
ひょっとして この仮面って
見つからないように？
That's right.
（リーン）そうよ
I didn't want to get dragged
home before I found you two.
あなたたちを見つける前に
連れ戻されたらイヤだから
Sorry I lied about it being a gift.
ごめんね プレゼントなんて
ウソ言って
Are you disappointed?
ガッカリした？
あ…
Have it back.
（グーグー）返すよ
Thanks for lending me the mask.
ありがとう 仮面 貸してくれて
I understand you a little better now.
おかげで
君のことが少し分かったよ
Don't worry, I won't look at you.
（リーン）
安心して そっち見ないから
It doesn't matter anymore.
（グーグー）別に もう…
Thanks.
ありがとう
I got it!
（フシ）とってきた！
（グーグー）うわっ
Fushi-san!
（リーン）フシさん
All right, let's go back to Booze Man's place.
（グーグー）
さあて 酒爺の所へ帰ろうか
Are you sure?
（リーン）えっ いいの？
さっきは帰りたくないって
You said you didn't want to go back earlier.
That's the best place for you, isn't it?
（グーグー）あそこが君にとって
一番いい場所なんでしょ？
Yeah.
（リーン）うん…
But are you not angry at
the old man anymore?
でも もう おじいさんのことは
怒ってないの？
I don't care anymore,
（グーグー）
もう どうでもよくなった
about what he did to me or how I felt.
何されたとか
自分が どう感じたとか
It's not that I've forgiven him...
別に 許したとか
そうゆうのじゃなくて…
（ミールがじゃれる声）
But I've lost interest in
my own circumstances.
（グーグー）ただ 自分の境遇に
興味がなくなった
That's all.
それだけ
So I can go back now.
だから もう帰れる 帰ろう
Let's go.
Okay.
（リーン）うん！
（侍女）ハッ
Young lady!
お嬢さま！
Where have you been?
一体どこに行ってらしたのですか！
You aren't going to fool me with that mask.
仮面で ごまかそうたって
そうはいきません
Let's go home.
さあ帰りましょう
お父さま方が心配なさっていますよ
Your father and the others
are worried about you.
You must have the wrong person.
（リーン）人違いでは？
リーンなんて知らないわ
I don't know of a Rean.
（侍女）ホホホ…
相変わらず おかわいいこと
You're as endearing as ever.
I never said "Rean."
わたくしは ひと言も
リーンとは言ってませんわよ
Now surrender, and let's go home.
さあ 観念して帰りましょう
No way. That's such a pain.
（リーン）ヤダよ 面倒くさいよ…
Just ignore her!
（侍女）あっ
（グーグー）無視すればいい！
（グーグーとリーンの荒い息）
Young lady!
（侍女）お嬢さま… お嬢さま！
Oh, no! She's still following me!
（リーン）イヤ ついてくるわ
There'll be trouble if she follows us home.
（グーグー）
家まで来られると厄介だな
Fushi, take care of her.
（グーグー）フシ 頼む！
（フシ）うん
Okay.
Wait!
待って… ハァ お嬢さ…
Young la—
（侍女）キャッ
（フシ）うあ…
（侍女）イタッ… 何なの この子！
Who is this child?
（フシ）ううう…
What shall I do?
（侍女）まあ どうしましょう
（フシ）
いたい いたい…
It hurts.
It hurts. It hurts.
あっ！
She's bleeding! Oh, no!
いたい いたい…
血が出てる… 大変！
（荒い息）
There it is! We're almost home!
（グーグー）
見えた！　もうすぐ家だ
Hey, what about Fushi-san?
（リーン）ねえ フシさんは？
Don't worry. He'll be right with us.
（グーグー）大丈夫 すぐ来るよ
I don't know about that.
（観察者）さあ… どうだろうか
I don't think he will.
おそらく戻らない
For two reasons.
理由は２つある
First, he hasn't acquired anything
of use since the last battle.
１つ目
前の戦い以降
有用なものを獲得していない
Second, it made the first move.
２つ目 先手を打たれた
（侍女）え？　キャー！
Was that a scream?
（２人）ん？
今の 悲鳴？
Fushi sure is making a scene.
（グーグー）
派手にやってるな フシ
Somebody! Somebody help!
（侍女）
誰か… 誰か助けて 怪物が！
It's a monster!
A monster?
（グーグー）え？
（リーン）怪物？
I'll go take a look. Go home, I'll be right there.
（グーグー）ちょっと
見てくる 先に帰ってて
Wait!
Don't leave me by myself!
（リーン）
待って！　私を１人に…
Huh?
（グーグー）え？
I said I can go back by myself.
あ… １人…
で帰れるって言ったの
Right. Get back safe.
（グーグー）
うん じゃあ気をつけてね
Okay. You, too.
（リーン）
ええ あなたも！
（グーグー）ハァハァハァ…
Fushi!
フシ！
What the... Was that blood?
うわっ 何だ 血か？
あっ
Fushi!
フシ！
フシ！　フシ！　フシ！
Fushi! Fushi!
ん？
What is this?
何だよ これ？
な…
Preview
The unknowable enemy has come again.
（観察者）
再び現れた得体の知れない敵
Fushi is attacked viciously in the forest.
森の中で猛攻撃を受けるフシ
Gugu rushes to his aid.
助けに走るグーグー
The bond between the brothers
offers a narrow escape from death.
兄弟の絆(きずな)は
起死回生の一手を生み出す
New Family